# PRABAKARAN.P

## **Contact**

thanuvenbaa@gmail.com

+91-7010014984 +91-8508952852

## **Education**

B.E. ECE SSM Engineering College

# **Technical Skills**

AWS Services, IAM, EC2,S3,Load Balancers, Auto Scaling, EBS,EFS, ROUTE 53, Cloud Watch, Cloud Front, VPC,SNS,SQS, RDS, Dynamo DB, SEO, SEM, C, NoSQL DB.

## **Expertise**

AWS Cloud Engineer Linux Support (L1) Digital Marketing Analyst Technical Support - Team Lead Implementation Engineer

#### **Professional Profile**

To work in a creative and challenging environment where I could constantly learn and successfully deliver solutions to problems and contribute effectively for the growth of the Organization.

Having 2 Years of experience in AWS Services & Linux Support 2 Years of experience in Digital Marketing Services. 3 Years 3 Month of experience in Technical Support - Team Lead 1 Years & 10 Month of experience as a Product Implementation Engineer.

### **Work Experience**

Organization: Efforts Solutions IT, Chennai.

**Duration**: Apr 2020 To Till Date

Role : AWS Cloud Support & Linux

### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Working as a part of the AWS, Build, Designed & Deployed applications utilizing almost all of AWS, Including EC2 (Elastic Compute Cloud), S3 (Simple Storage Service), IAM (Identity Access Management), SNS (Simple Notification Service), VPC (Virtual Private Cloud), SES (Simple Email Service), Cloud Watch, EFS (Elastic File System), Elastic Load Balancer (Classic/Application), Route53, Auto Scaling in launching EC2 instances, Cloud Trail, RDS, AWS CLI (Command Line Interface), Cloud Front, and DB Snapshots.
- Build Servers using AWS EC2, created security Groups, configured Auto scaling groups and Load balancers (CLB & ALB) in defined virtual private connection.
- Responsible for creating monitors, alarms and notifications for EC2 hosts using Cloud Watch and SNS service.
- VPC, Public and Private Subnet, Route table.
- Created many users, placed users into their respective groups and given limited privileges to directly to users groups to have better security.
- Created snapshots to take backups of the volumes and images to store launch configurations of the EC2 instances.
- Basic Level support of Red hat & Cent OS servers
- Remove older rotated log files to free up the disk space.
- Worked on creating and removing files and directories in Linux servers.
- Monitoring health of Amazon EC2 instances and other AWS services.

Organization: Efforts Solutions IT, Chennai Duration: May 2018 To Apr 2020

Role : Digital Marketing Analyst & Linux System Support

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Manage the SEO Onsite & Offsite of the E- Commerce website.
- Adjust the Bidding in google ads as per current status.
- Google Ads, Facebook Ads, Email Marketing
- Implementing the new things to improve the daily sales and generating reports on monthly basis.
- Proactive monitoring of Client issue logs and escalating to the right team.
- Perform error management, incident management, change & release management (JIRA)
- Communicating with third party technical specialists.
- Giving support to client to solving any issue of Backend.
- Providing backend support for E-commerce website (Shopify).

**Organization: Prime Focus Technologies, Bangalore.** 

Duration: Feb 2015 To Apr 2018

Role : Team Lead – Technical Support

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Providing the CMS Backend Support to Hotstar Application.
- Cataloguing Team and Content Team by ensuring the flawless deliveries to Hotstar.
- By leading the team, we had delivered approx. 150 Hrs. of content on a daily basis (4 Days).
- Resolving Issues and Complete the client requirements.
- Handled all queries and client feedback in a professional manner.
- Communicated and implemented the organization's operational guidelines, standards and policies.
- Ensuring that the deliverables are made on time with 100% compliance.
- Designed and coordinated training programs for employees in order to enhance work efficiency.
- Proactive monitoring of customer application logs and escalating to the right team.
- Perform error management, incident management, change & release management (JIRA)

**Organization: Arya IT Solutions, Sathyamangalam.** 

Duration: Mar 2013 To Dec 2014

Role : Product Implementation Engineer

### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Giving support to Developers team for any modification & changes in the CMS application.
- Installed and tested Application on client servers and workstations and supported end users for period of time after implementation.
- Provided suggestions and guidance on future solution enhancements and development as per client requirements.
- Installation of various operating systems like Windows 2007 and Linux operating system.
- Provide secondary support for LAN administration.
- Resolve complex IT support issues.
- Communicating with third party technical specialists.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

Subject	Board/University	College/Institution	Year of Passing	Percentage
B.E ECE	Anna university, Coimbatore	SSM Engineering College, Komarapalayam.	2011	63.46%
Diploma (DECE)	DOTE (Directorate of Technical Education)	Anndavar Polytechnic College, Gobi.	2008	76%
SSLC	Tamil Nadu Secondary Education Examination Board	Diamond Jubilee Higher Secondary School, Gobi.	2003	75%

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Chennai

Date: PRABAKARAN.P